🛘 +39 334 8756245 | 🔀 roberto.bigazzi.1995@gmail.com | 🌴 robertobigazzi.it | 🖸 bigazzon | 🛅 roberto-bigazzi

#### Summary

I am a machine learning engineer and data scientist at Ferrari. I was a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, working on Computer Vision and Deep Learning for Embodied Al. I completed my Ph.D. at AlmageLab supervised by Professor Rita Cucchiara. During my Master's, I studied at the Polytechnic University of Milan. I also spent a period as a visiting student researcher at Stanford University's Autonomous Systems Lab under Professor Marco Pavone.

## **Knowledge and Technical Skills**

**Topics** Visual Navigation, Multimodal Learning, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning

Programming Python, Java, Javascript, C++, C#, C, MATLAB, SQL, Microcontroller Programming (Arduino)

Languages Italian (Mothertongue), English (Proficient TOEIC (C1), FCE (B2))

### Experience

Machine Learning Engineer and Data Scientist @ Ferrari SpA

Learning-based Approaches for Automotive Research and Development

Postdoctoral Research Fellow @ AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Computer Vision and Deep Learning Research: Visual Navigation and Multimodal Learning for Embodied Agents

Research Fellow @ AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Research on Embodied AI during Doctorate at AlmageLab

Research Fellow @ ASL - Stanford University

Research on Visual Navigation at Autonomous Systems Lab

Lecturer @ Nuova Didactica, Prometeia, and IFOA

"Deep Learning Application" course

Maranello, Modena, Italy Mar. 2023 - present

> Modena, Italy Mar. 2023 - present

Modena, Italy Nov. 2019 - Mar. 2023

Stanford, California, United States

Jun. 2022 - Aug. 2022

Modena / Bologna, Italy Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2024

## **Education**

Ph.D. @ University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Doctorate in Information and Communication Technologies under the supervision of Prof. Rita Cucchiara

Visiting Student Researcher @ Stanford University

Research on Visual Navigation at Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL) under the supervision of Prof. Marco Pavone

Erasmus+ Student @ Technische Universität Wien

Erasmus+ Exchange Semester

B.S. and M.S. @ Polytechnic University of Milan

Bachelor of Science and Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (Thesis with Prof. Marco Gribaudo)

Modena, Italy Nov. 2019 - Mar. 2023

Stanford, California, USA

May 2022 - Aug. 2022 Vienna, Austria

Oct. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Milan, Italy

Sep. 2014 - Oct. 2019

#### **Main Pubblications**

2024 Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)

Personalized Instance-based Navigation Toward User-Specific Objects in Realistic Environments

2024 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) (Collaboration with Stanford University and Georgia Tech)

Mapping High-level Semantic Regions in Indoor Environments without Object Recognition

2024 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW)

AIGeN: An Adversarial Approach for Instruction Generation in Vision-and-Language Navigation

2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

**Embodied Agents for Efficient Exploration and Smart Scene Description** 

2022 IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) + IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Focus on Impact: Indoor Exploration with Intrinsic Motivation

2020 25th IAPR International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR) (Oral Presentation)

Explore and Explain: Self-supervised Navigation and Recounting

2023 22st International Conference on Image Analysis and Processing (ICIAP) (Honorable Mention for ICIAP Best Paper Award)

**Towards Explainable Embodied Navigation and Recounting** 

## **Program Committees**

Outstanding Reviewer Award: ECCV 2024. Evaluator, ELLIS Ph.D. Program.

Peer Reviewer: Conferences - CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, ICRA, IROS, WACV, ICPR, ACMMM, ICIAP; Journals - RA-L, GRSL, PRL, TOMM.

# **Teaching Activities**

Teaching Assistant: "Computer Architectures", "Al for Automotive", and "Computer Vision and Cognitive Systems" courses.

**Assistant Supervisor:** 3x Student Theses on Deep Learning and Computer Vision.

According to law 679/2016 of the Regulation of the European Parliament of 27th April 2016, I hereby express my consent to process and use my data provided in this document and application for recruiting purposes.

Roberto Bigazzi · Resume